Guide to Ralph Anderson, Jr. papers, 1860-1989 MS 413
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Ralph Anderson Jr. Papers
1860-1989
bulk
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Anderson, Ralph, Jr.
MS 413
11 Linear Feet (23 boxes)
Houston-born Ralph Anderson Jr. (1923-1990) studied architecture at Rice Institute and earned a bachelor's degree in 1943. He was inducted into the U.S. Army in 1943 and fought in the Battle of the Bulge where he was wounded and awarded a medal for his bravery. After the war, he returned to Rice and continued his studies in architecture. He joined the architectural firm of Wilson, Morris and Crain and eventually rose to become a partner and later president of the company. The papers cover a broad spectrum of Ralph Anderson's life, including his family, school, university years, his combat service in World War II with the U.S. Army, and his professional life as an architect.
Biographical / Historical
Ralph Anderson, Jr. was born January 1, 1923 in Houston, Texas, the son of Mr. And Mrs. Ralph Anderson, Sr. Ralph Anderson, Sr. (Andy) was the Sports Editor of the Houston Post and later the Houston Press.
Ralph Anderson, Jr. attended school in Houston, graduating from Lamar High School in 1939 and Rice Institute (later Rice University) in 1943 with a B. A. degree in Architecture. While at Rice, he won The American Institute of Architecture Student Medal, and was the first architectural student at the university to be elected to Phi Beta Kappa, a national honorary fraternity.
After being inducted into the Army in 1943, he was sent to Harvard University. Upon completion of an Advanced Studies Program, he went to France where he served in the European Theatre of Operations. As a result of a head wound received at the Battle of the Bulge, he was awarded both the Purple Heart and the Bronze Star.
When the war ended, Ralph Anderson returned to Rice Institute, and received a B. S. degree in Architecture in 1947. After graduating, he joined the firm of Wilson, Morris and Crain. He worked for two years, then took a leave of absence in 1949 for an extensive study tour of Europe. He returned to the firm in 1950 and was made a partner in 1952. In 1972 the firm became known as Wilson, Crain and Anderson and in 1975 it became Wilson, Crain, Anderson and Reynolds. He was President of Crain/Anderson, Inc. in 1978.
Ralph Anderson was an artist, book reviewer, lecturer and author. He took part in the 12th Annual Texas Painting and Sculpture Exhibit in 1951. He wrote Handcar White: The Battle History of 2nd Battalion, 328th Infantry Regiment WWII and Spain Today, plus numerous articles for architectural journals.
He was a registered architect in Texas, Indiana, Louisiana, the District of Columbia, Missouri, Kansas, North Carolina, Oklahoma and Ohio, and designed both family residences and commercial buildings. The World Trade Center in Houston, the Astrodome, Kelsey-Seybold Clinic, the Houston Post Building, the Harris Court House Addition, and the Alice Pratt Brown Fine Arts Library at Rice University were among his many designs.
He won numerous awards, such as the Award of Merit, Texas Architecture, 1961, 1965; The Commendation Award, Houston Chapter A. I. A. 1962; Interior Certificate of Commendation, Municipal Art Commission, 1973, and many more. He became President of the Houston Chapter of the American Institute of Architects in 1966 and was elected a Fellow in the A. I. A., in 1967.
Ralph Anderson was a member of Allegro, The Tejas Club of Houston, and the Argyle Club of San Antonio.
He died February 3, 1990 in Houston.
Scope and Contents
The Ralph Anderson Collection consists of correspondence, photographs, architectural drawings, publications, memorabilia, Rice University records and World War II records. It covers a broad spectrum of Ralph Anderson's life beginning with his grade school transcripts and ending with the very poignant diary that he kept through the last year of his life.
Although most of the documents relate to the personal and professional life and career of Ralph Anderson, Jr., there are also a few records pertaining to other family members.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Box 6A is stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The papers were a gift from H. Russell Pitman, executor of the Ralph Anderson Estate. They were received in June, August, September, October 1990 and January 1991.
Organization
The collection is divided into eleven series:
Missing Title
Series I: Family Documents, 1860-1965 - 2.5 inches Box 1
Series II: Rice University, 1939-1988, 5 inches Box 2
Series III: World War II, 1942-1947, 22.5 inches Boxes 3-7
Series IV: General Correspondence, 1941-1989, 5 inches Box 8
Series V: Family Correspondence, 1943-1950, 20 inches Boxes 9-12
Series VI: Professional Practice, 1946-1989, 5 inches Box 13
Series VII: Professional Affiliation, 1946-1989, 2.5 inches Box 14
Series VIII: Personal, 1937-1989, 22.5 inches Boxes 15-19
Series IX: Publications, 1948-1989, 2.5 inches Box 20
Series X: General Photographs, 1929-1977, 5 inches Box 21
Series XI: Oversize, 1900-1969, 20 inches Box 22
Index Terms
Subjects
Architects -- Texas; World War (1939-1945); Ardennes, Battle of the, 1944-1945; Architecture
Document Types
notes; brochures; architectural drawings (visual works); medals; clippings (information artifacts); diaries; transcripts; photographs; corrrespondence; legal documents
Subjects (Persons)
Anderson, Ralph, Jr.
- Series I: Family Documents, 1860-1965
  Scope and Contents note
  The earliest records in the collection, 1860-1965, can be found in the Family Documents Series. They include documents of a genealogical nature, such as marriage, birth, and naturalization records. Ralph Anderson's school transcripts and a few legal "land" records belonging to Ralph Anderson, Sr. are also in this series.
  - Subseries A: 1860-1965
    - Family History and Certificates, Baptism, Marriage, and Naturalization, 1860-1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Examination of Title to Stratford Place Property, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - School Records, Ralph Anderson, Jr., Grades 1 - 12, 1928-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lender's Lien Installment Note, Ralph Anderson, Sr., and L. H. Meinert, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ralph Anderson, Sr. Memorial, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Claims Release, Ralph Anderson, Jr. and Dinish Shah, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Rice University, 1939-1988
  This series covers the years Ralph Anderson attended Rice University both before and after World War II. Included are class notes, financial records, school transcripts, membership in Phi Beta Kappa, and drawings for homes designed and built by Ralph Anderson while a student at Rice. There are also correspondence and newspaper clippings from a news column written by Ralph Anderson while serving as Class Agent.
  - Subseries A: 1939-1988
    - Financial, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Grades and Transcripts, 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Rice Scholarship List, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Architectural Society of Rice, 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - News Clippings, Class Agent, Architectural Society, 1940-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photos: Homes Designed by Ralph Anderson, 1941-42 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Drawings: Woodridge House, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Class Notes: Architecture 430, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Class Notes: Graphic Status and Strength of Materials, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Architectural Drawings, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - University Review, 1942 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Memorabilia: Class of 1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Memorabilia, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Seminar Paper, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Rome Prize Fellowship Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fondren Library Booklet Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Class of 1943: Golden Anniversary Scholarship Fund Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Architecture 210, Class Notes, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series III: World War II, 1942-1947
  Material in this series spans the years Ralph Anderson served in the army during World War II, beginning with his attendance at Harvard University, where he was enrolled in an Advanced Studies Program. There is also an extensive collection of photographs taken throughout Europe during World War II. Both the American and German memorabilia will be of interest to anyone doing research into World War II history. Included are patches, ribbons, German belt buckle, pins, a German slide rule, and a Safe Conduct Pass. Ralph Anderson's helmet (with bullet hole), his Good Conduct Medal and Bronze Star are included.
  - Subseries A: Harvard University
    - Notebooks, A.S.T.P., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Information Booklet, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts, Class Notes, and Schedules, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Memorabilia, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Memorabilia, Paper
    - Military Service Records, 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Identification Cards, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Military Passes, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Guidebooks: U. S. and Europe (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Maps: U. S. and Europe (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings (see Oversize), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Military Histories: History of 328th Infantry Division and 26th Infantry Division (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous, 1944-45 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Commendations, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Army Intelligence Records, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Army Headquarters Orders, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Historical Summaries, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Memorabilia, Realia
    - Hats, Patches, Dog Tags, Pins and Ribbons (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Plaque (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - German Compass, Safe Conduct Pass, Belt Buckle, Stamp and Pins (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Slide Rule (German) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - G.I. Helmet (Vault) (Box 6a)
    - Good Conduct Medal (Vault) (Box 6a)
    - Bronze Star (Vault) (Box 6a)
    - Military insignias and badges (Vault) (Box 6a)
  - Subseries D: World War II Photographs
    - Harvard University, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Normandy, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Metz, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - William Moore, Jr., 1944 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Czechoslovakia, Obermoldau, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Prachatice, Czechoslovakia, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Training Camp at Hetzlos, Germany, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Occupation in Austria, Reid, Linz, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Camp Pittsburg, Germany, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Camp Boston, Germany, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Reims Cathedral, Germany, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - France, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Combat in the Bulge, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Luxembourg, Saer, Germany, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Returning to the U. S., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ralph Anderson (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Ralph Anderson and Parent (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified, Riviera, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Negatives (Box 7, Folder 19)
      General note
      (See Oversize for additional photos)
- Series IV: General Correspondence, 1941-1989
  Letters in the general series have been divided by correspondence received by Ralph Anderson and correspondence sent by Ralph Anderson. Chronological order has been imposed on each group.
  While the majority of the correspondence in the general series relates to Ralph Anderson, Jr., there are some interesting letters written to his father, Andy Anderson, Sr. from Vice President Nixon in 1953 and from President Eisenhower in 1953 and 1954.
  - Subseries A: Letters, Greeting Cards and Post Cards
    - Received by Ralph Anderson, 1941-1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Received by Ralph Anderson, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Received by Ralph Anderson, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Received by Ralph Anderson (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sent by Ralph Anderson, 1950-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Vice President Nixon to Andy Anderson, Sr., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - President Eisenhower to Andy Anderson, Sr., 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Greeting Cards, 1931-1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Post Cards Sent by Ralph Anderson, 1945-1952 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Post Cards Received by Ralph Anderson, 1947-1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Series V: Family Correspondence, 1943-1950
  Most of the correspondence in the family series was written by Ralph Anderson, Jr. to his parents while serving in the army during World War II.
  - Subseries A: Family Correspondence; Mr. and Mrs. R.A. Anderson Sr. from Ralph Anderson, Jr., 1943 (Box 9, Folder 1-8)
  - Subseries B: Family Correspondence; Mr. and Mrs. R.A. Anderson Sr. from Ralph Anderson, Jr., 1944 (Box 10, Folder 1-12)
  - Subseries C: Family Correspondence; Mr. and Mrs. R.A. Anderson Sr. from Ralph Anderson, Jr., 1945 (Box 11, Folder 1-11)
  - Subseries D: Family Correspondence; Mr. and Mrs. R.A. Anderson Sr. from Ralph Anderson, Jr., 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 1-19)
    - Letters from Ralph Anderson (Box 12, Folder 1-15)
    - Post Cards, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Post Cards, 1945-1949 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Post Cards, 1950-1958 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Post Cards, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Professional Practice, 1946-1989
  This series covers the entire span of his career from his early work to his retirement in 1989. There are newspaper clippings and correspondence from his many years of association with Wilson, Morris, and Crain and later when the firm became Wilson, Morris, Crain and Anderson. There are also financial records, brochures, and rendering from various architectural projects. To see the architectural drawings from Ralph Anderson's career, see the list of contents in Map Drawer 2. Included in the drawings are personal dwellings, medical clinics, banks, schools, T. V. Stations and the Harris County Sports Stadium (Astrodome) built in 1965.
  - Subseries A: Drawings, Correspondence, Renderings
    - Clipping from the Houston Press titled "Solar" Modern Designed for Small Lot, Friday, Jan. 10, 1947. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      See Ralph Anderson's drawings in map drawer 2 for house plans.
    - Financial, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - New Clippings/Wilson, Morris, Crain and Anderson, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Resume, Ralph Anderson, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Residential Work of Ralph Anderson, 1949-1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Drawings, Specifications, Correspondence
    - Drawings and Specifications for Edwin Smith Home, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Specifications, Correspondence, Financial Statments related to Edwin Smith home, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Photographs Unidentified House, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Badge, Dedication Ceremonies WISH T. V., 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Brochures, Renderings and Drawings/Wilson, Morris and Crain Architects (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Perspective Proposed Shopping Center/Lloyd and Morgan, Architects (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Rendering, Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C: Ralph A. Anderson, Jr. Drawings (Item not specified)
    - A Decorator's Accessory, Class B-Problem 3 assignment; n.d.; 2 photostatic copies; renderings, sections. (Drawer #2, Item 1)
    - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. J. Edwin Smith, Houston; October 1, 1947; 10 drawings on paper; plans, details, elevations, sections., 1947-1948 (Drawer #2, Item 2)
    - Unidentified house at Tierwester and Oakdale; n.d.; 2 ink on paper, plan, site plan. (Drawer #2, Item 3)
    - School of Architecture for Rice Institute; Traveling Fellowship Competition; 1947; pen, pencil and watercolor on poster; perspective, floor plan. (Drawer #2, Item 4)
    - "A Thing of Beauty is a Joy Forever;" n.d.; pen and watercolor on poster. (Drawer #2, Item 5)
    - Color chart; n.d.; watercolor on paper. (Drawer #2, Item 6)
    - A Flagstaff; n.d.; class sketch-pencil and watercolor on poster. (Drawer #2, Item 7)
    - Greek temple; n.d.; pen and watercolor drawing on paper. (Drawer #2, Item 8)
    - Local Historical Museum; n.d.; class project; pen, pencil and watercolor on poster; site plan, elevation, section, perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 9)
    - House; Walsh Prize, 1943; pencil on board; floor plans, perspective, isometric of A/C system. (Drawer #2, Item 10)
    - Picnic shelter; n.d.; class project; ink on paper; floor plan, section. (Drawer #2, Item 11)
    - Residence for Mr. Mrs. Vance Trimble; 1946; original pencil on paper; 4 sheets; plans, sections, elevation, details. (Drawer #2, Item 12)
    - Fort Brown Women's Center, Brownsville, TX, Wiltshire Fisher; n.d.; blueprint, section. (Drawer #2, Item 13)
    - School of Architecture for Rice Institute; n.d. pen and watercolor on heavy paper; plot plan, section, elevations. (Drawer #2, Item 14)
    - Passarelle; n.d.; class project; watercolor and pencil on paper; plan, section, elevation. (Drawer #2, Item 15)
    - Park stairway and ramp; n.d.; class project; ink and watercolor on poster; site plan, perspective, elevation. (Drawer #2, Item 16)
    - Military Reviewing Stand; n.d.; pencil and watercolor on poster; perspective, elevation, plan, section. (Drawer #2, Item 17)
    - General office building for Houston, Texas; n.d.; graduate thesis; six photostatic copies: floor plans, roof plan, elevation, section. (Drawer #2, Item 18)
    - Anderson townhouse; 5-11-60; 4 pencil on paper, foundation, site and framing plan. (Drawer #2, Item 19)
    - Anderson townhouse addition; 2-22-73; pencil on paper; sections, floor plan. (Drawer #2, Item 20)
    - Redwood Court Deck for R.A.A. Residence; 3-23-64; pencil on paper; court plan, section. (Drawer #2, Item 21)
    - Unidentified townhouse; n.d.; 2 pencil tracings. (Drawer #2, Item 22)
    - "James J. Smith on 'Wood in Architecture'"; n.d.; poster for lecture on wood in architecture; watercolor on paper. (Drawer #2, Item 23)
    - Service Men's Center; n.d.; class project; ink and water-color on poster; perspective, elevation, plot plan, section, floor plan. (Drawer #2, Item 24)
    - Small stores development; Kawneer Prize, 1942; pencil and watercolor on poster; elevation, plan, section, perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 25)
    - Theatre des Enfants; n.d.; watercolor perspective on paper; section, plan. (Drawer #2, Item 26)
    - War Memorial; n.d.; class project; ink and watercolor on poster; site plan, elevation, section, detail. (Drawer #2, Item 27)
    - Pulpit; n.d.; pen and watercolor perspective on paper, plan. (Drawer #2, Item 28)
    - Rest Camp for Veterans; n.d.; pencil and tempura paint on poster board; site plan; cabin floorplan. (Drawer #2, Item 29)
    - Lake house; n.d.; charcoal, chalk and pencil on board; floor plan, section. (Drawer #2, Item 30)
    - Townhouse plan; 5-60; 12 prints on paper; plans, elevations, sections, details; 2 negatives (Anderson residence on Banks St.) (Drawer #2, Item 31)
    - Diplomas, awards and certificates. (Drawer #2, Item 32)
    - Fondren Library interior; 1947, 7 pencil sketches. (Drawer #2, Item 33)
    - Learning Foundation; August 12, 1970; 2 blueprints; floor and ceiling plans, elevations, sections. (Drawer #2, Item 34)
    - "Existing 2-storey house;" 4-18-73; 1 pencil on paper; 1 photocopy; sections, floor plan. (Drawer #2, Item 35)
    - Domed stadium; n.d.; 2 blueprints; perspectives. (Drawer #2, Item 36)
    - Office building; 1960; mylar; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 37)
    - Fence for apartment building; n.d.; pencil on trace, pencil on paper; perspective, sections. (Drawer #2, Item 38)
    - A Clinic Building; n.d.; 2 photocopies on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 39)
    - Store building; n.d.; pencil on paper; rendering. (Drawer #2, Item 40)
    - Apartments and marina; n.d.; 2 blueprints, 3 transparencies; perspectives. (Drawer #2, Item 41)
    - Pipe organ; n.d.; perspective; ink on paper. (Drawer #2, Item 42)
    - Preliminary sketch for Mr. Mrs. Vernon Frost; n.d.; 2 mylar, 2 pencil on paper, 1 photocopy, 2 negatives; perspectives, floorplan. (Drawer #2, Item 43)
    - Flower; n.d.; blueprint; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 44)
    - Playing card or poster; n.d.; color on shiny paper. (Drawer #2, Item 45)
    - House; n.d.; pencil on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 46)
    - Memorial Hospital building; n.d.; pencil on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 47)
    - Apartment project for B.B. Frances Yeager; n.d.; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 48)
    - Apartment building; n.d.; pencil on paper. (Drawer #2, Item 49)
    - Store building; n.d.; colored pencil on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 50)
    - Studio apartment for R.A. Anderson, 1214 Miramar; December 3, 1965; 3 blueprints; 1 plat of property; pencil on paper; plans, elevations, sections. (Drawer #2, Item 51)
    - Garage apartment for Mr. R.A. Anderson, Jr.; June 21, 1965, September 18, 1965; 3 pencil on paper; plans, sections, details, specs. (Drawer #2, Item 52)
    - Townhouses for Ralph Anderson; September 18, 1970, revised October 7, 1979; blueprint; site plan, roof and floorplans. (Drawer #2, Item 53)
    - Townhouses; November 16, 1965; mylar, pencil on paper; 3 site plans, 2 floor plans, 3 photocopies, skylite details. (Drawer #2, Item 54)
    - Lexington townhouses;; 75 pencil on paper and trace; site plan, elevations, sections, plans. (Drawer #2, Item 55)
    - Apartment or house; n.d.; pencil on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 56)
    - Residence for Mr. C. Thomas Wright; September 1972; 20 blueprints; site plan, plans, elevations, sections, schedules: door, room finish, plumbing fixture, lighting. (Drawer #2, Item 57)
    - Office building for Kelley Mfg. Co.; n.d.; pencil on paper; perspective, floorplan. (Drawer #2, Item 58)
    - Bank building for Mr. Frank W. Sharp; n.d.; pencil on paper and photocopy; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 59)
    - Residence for Mr. Mrs. Maurice Lazarus; n.d.; pencil on paper; perspective. (Drawer #2, Item 60)
    - Ralph Anderson's townhouse; May 1960; 8 blueprints; site plan, framing, foundation, floor, elevations, sections, details. (Drawer #2, Item 61)
    - Townhouses for Ralph Anderson; July 15, 1970; blueprint; site plan, elevation. (Drawer #2, Item 62)
    - Unidentified project; n.d.; 2 pencil on paper perspectives. (Drawer #2, Item 63)
    - Unidentified project; n.d.; 1 negative; floor plan. (Drawer #2, Item 64)
    - Apartment unit; March 31, 1965; 6 pencil on trace; plans, sections, elevations. (Drawer #2, Item 65)
- Series VII: Professional Affiliation, 1946-1989
  Ralph Anderson's professional affiliations are closely tied to his professional practice. This series contains brochures, drawings, and lectures given by Ralph Anderson. There is also some interesting correspondence relating to his association with the Texas Architects Committee, the Texas Society of Architects, and the American Institute of Architects. Of particular interest are the many letters of congratulations Ralph Anderson received when he was nominated for a "Fellowship" in the American Institute of Architects.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Memberships
    - Texas Society of Architects, 1946-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Architects, Houston Chapter, Honor Award, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - American Institute of Architects, Le Brun Scholarship, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)